# JOSE RAMON PRIETO DEL PRADO

#### WORK EXPERIENCE



# **Software Engineer**

**UST Global** 

August 2022 - Actual

Implementation and maintenance of JAVA application that receives a significant amount of data traffic through MQ queues and web services, so it is necessary to implement a code as efficient as possible, with many unit, integration and system tests.



# Junior Software Engineer

**Stratesys** 

February 2022 - August 2022

Implementation and maintenance of APIs and microservices with Spring Boot. Developing and thinking models for new projects and implementing them from scratch with JPA. Maintenance of several web projects with Angular JS, VueJS and CI/CD optimization of our projects.



#### **Full Stack Software Developer**

**Pixelware** 

March 2018 - September 2018

Implementation of new endpoints for the APIs of our projects with Spring. Adding new functionality to the model of some of our projects using JPA.

## PROJECTS AND ABILITIES

- FinanzYou. Financial application that allows you to manage your portfolio, where you can see a complete description of your portfolio. In addition, the application contains a lot of charts showing your profit or loss history and many more data about your portfolio such as news, etc... Application available at <a href="mailto:finanzyoufront.herokuapp.com">finanzyoufront.herokuapp.com</a> and source code available at <a href="mailto:github.com/jprieto96/finanz-you-frontend">github.com/jprieto96/finanz-you-backend</a>.
- **MySeries**. Android application for the management of series, movies and TV shows made with Java and released in the Play Store. Source code availabe at <a href="mailto:gitlab.com/jprieto96/myseries">gitlab.com/jprieto96/myseries</a>
- Portfolio of the rest of smaller projects I'm doing in my GitHub like minigames or miniprojects, exercises about data structures, trying and testing other programming languages, new frameworks, libraries, etc...github.com/jprieto96



### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

linkedin.com/in/jose-ramonprieto-del-prado

joseprieto9657@gmail.com

+34 682898814

github.com/jprieto96

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

Software engineer with 1+ year of experience working mainly on implementing and maintaining microservices with Spring Boot. Although Java is the technology I have the most experience in, the technology is not the important thing, as it is the easiest part to learn, so most of my time is spent analysing and detecting problems, looking for a good solution and a good technique to solve it.

### **EDUCATION HISTORY**



Software Engineering Universidad Complutense de Madrid 2018-2022

Average Mark: **8.28**/10. Honors Degree obtained in Data Structures (2020) and Advanced Databases (2021)



**Computer Science University of Hertfordshire**2021-2022

Exchange student for one semester through the Erasmus 21/22 program